Ginn Library Records UA198
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Ginn Library Records
1931 -- 2010
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Edwin Ginn Library
Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy
UA198
4.7 Linear Feet 5 boxes and 1 oversize folder
2 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Annual reports; Subject files; and Photographs and posters.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records created by and related to the Edwin Ginn Library in the Fletcher School and includes correspondence, ledgers, minutes, posters, reports, serials, and subject files.
Related Materials
UA137, Tisch Library records, DCA.
Biographical / Historical
The Edwin Ginn Library (1938-present) was established in 1938 as the official library for the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy (Graduate School of International Affairs). The library was named after donor Edwin Ginn, a former Tufts alumnus who graduated in 1862, and who made significant financial gifts to the university over the course of his life.
Prior to the establishment of the Ginn Library, the materials that started the library collection were part of Ginn's personal collection and were called the Library for World Peace Foundation. The library was originally intended to be a research collection for graduate students (Light on the Hill, 592).
As of 2011, the Edwin Ginn Library provides collections, services and technology that anticipate and meet the research and instructional needs of The Fletcher School. The Library maintains a research and study environment conducive to exploration, discovery and knowledge creation. The library's collection of primary and secondary reference and research materials has been developed with attention to the content of The Fletcher School curriculum and the research interests of students and faculty. The library contains over 120,000 volumes, including 270 current periodicals and serials. The Tufts University Libraries share over 30,000 electronic publications and databases. Ginn Library's collection covers the fields of international law and organizations; human rights; economic and political development; international energy resources and environmental matters; international security and peacekeeping; conflict negotiation; international business and finance; and the uses of the sea and outer space. The Ginn Library entrance is located on the first floor of the Mugar building.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. The Subject files series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Academic Support -- Libraries, Galleries, Archives; Advancement
- Annual Reports, 1933 -- 1999; 1975 -- 1990; UA198.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the annual reports of the Ginn Library. Most of the reports were written between 1975 and 1990. The majority of the reports were written by the Ginn Head Librarian. While most of the reports are titled "Annual Report," a few bear other titles such as "Report to the Dean" or "Report of the Reference Librarian." These reports address the overall state of the Ginn Library between 1933 and 1999.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by report type and then chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Annual Reports, 1966 -- 1982; UA198.001.001.00001 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1982 -- 1983; UA198.001.001.00002 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1983 -- 1984; UA198.001.001.00003 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1984 -- 1985; UA198.001.001.00004 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1986 -- 1995; UA198.001.001.00005 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1995 -- 1996; UA198.001.001.00006 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1981 -- 1999; UA198.001.001.00007 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Books Loaned, 1983 -- 1984; UA198.001.001.00008 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Reports of the Research Librarian, 1933 -- 1959; UA198.001.001.00009 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Reports to the Dean, 1960 -- 1970; UA198.001.001.00010 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Reports to the Dean, 1970 -- 1978; UA198.001.001.00011 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Reports to the Dean, 1948 -- 1981; UA198.001.001.00012 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Reports to the Dean, 1981 -- 1982; UA198.001.001.00013 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
  - Reports of the University Librarian, 1936 -- 1981; UA198.001.001.00014 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
- Subject Files, 1931 -- 2008; 1979 -- 1985; UA198.002; 3.65 Linear Feet
  This series contains subject files created by the Ginn Library. Most of these materials were created between 1979 and 1985. The subject files cover a broad array of topics, including library acquisitions, administration (including a heated debate over whether or not the Ginn Library should be independent of the Wessel/Tisch Library), information about the building and the remodeling of the building, committee meeting minutes, and circulation statistics.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject using the original titles of folders.
  - Subject Files, 1931 -- 2006; UA198.002.001
    - Acquisitions, Selected Recent, 1970 -- 1973; UA198.002.001.00015 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Acquisitions, Selected Recent, 1974 -- 1978; UA198.002.001.00016 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Acquisitions, Selected Recent, 1979 -- 1982; UA198.002.001.00017 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Administration, 1971 -- 1977; UA198.002.001.00018 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Architects Floor Plans, 1980 -- 1981; UA198.002.001.00019 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Architects Lighting Plans, 1979 -- 1981; UA198.002.001.00020 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Board of Overseers to the Library, 1983 -- 1999; UA198.002.001.00021 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Board of Visitors - Tufts University, 1974 -- 1984; UA198.002.001.00022 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Building Committee, 1975 -- 1976; UA198.002.001.00023 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Building Matters, 1981 -- 1997; UA198.002.001.00024 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Building Plans, 1980; UA198.002.001.00025 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - By-Laws, 1991 -- 1997; UA198.002.001.00026 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - CIC Gazette, 1980 -- 1982; UA198.002.001.00027 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
      Folder title should read: ICC [Intercultural Center] Gazette.
    - Committee on the Disruption, 1980 -- 1981; UA198.002.001.00028 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Committee on the Size of the Student Body, 1981; UA198.002.001.00029 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Exhibits, 1979 -- 1992; UA198.002.001.00030 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Fletcher Library, 1943 -- 1981; UA198.002.001.00031 (Box UA198 Shared 1)
    - Fletcher School, 1931 -- 1984; UA198.002.002.00001 (Box 2)
    - Fletcher School & Library History, 2006; UA198.002.002.00002 (Box 2)
    - Fletcher/Tufts Library Matters, 1982; UA198.002.002.00003 (Box 2)
    - Furniture and Budget, 1980 -- 1981; UA198.002.002.00004 (Box 2)
    - In-House Statistics, 1983 -- 1997; UA198.002.002.00005 (Box 2)
    - Library Automation, 1979 -- 1982; UA198.002.002.00006 (Box 2)
    - Library Book Funds, 1983 -- 1996; UA198.002.002.00007 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee, 1971 -- 1974; UA198.002.002.00008 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee, 1965 -- 1979; UA198.002.002.00009 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee, 1984 -- 1990; UA198.002.002.00010 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee, 1990 -- 1995; UA198.002.002.00011 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee, 1995 -- 1997; UA198.002.002.00012 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee, 1997 -- 1998; UA198.002.002.00013 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee and Related Materials, 1974 -- 1975; UA198.002.002.00014 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee and Related Materials, 1975 -- 1979; UA198.002.002.00015 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee Staff Meetings, 1971 -- 1973; UA198.002.002.00016 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee Staff Meetings, 1974 -- 1975; UA198.002.002.00017 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee Staff Meetings, 1980 -- 1984; UA198.002.002.00018 (Box 2)
    - Material Relating to Fire and Water Damage, 1971; UA198.002.002.00019 (Box 2)
    - Model Intercultural Center Documents, 1977; UA198.002.002.00020 (Box 2)
    - Office Supplies - Inventory, 1982 -- 1984; UA198.002.002.00021 (Box 2)
    - Opening, 1981; UA198.002.002.00022 (Box 2)
    - Promotional Bookmarks, UA198.002.002.00023 (Box 2)
    - Space Requirements, 1974 -- 1982; UA198.002.002.00024 (Box 2)
    - Statements, 1933 -- 1975; UA198.002.002.00025 (Box 2)
    - Statistics - Annual - Fletcher, 1965 -- 1975; UA198.002.003.00001 (Box 3)
    - Statistics - Annual - Fletcher, 1975 -- 1982; UA198.002.003.00002 (Box 3)
    - Statistics, 1984 -- 1985; UA198.002.003.00003 (Box 3)
    - Statistics, 1988 -- 1989; UA198.002.003.00004 (Box 3)
    - Statistics, 1989 -- 1990; UA198.002.003.00005 (Box 3)
    - Statistics, 1990 -- 1991; UA198.002.003.00006 (Box 3)
    - Statistics, 1991 -- 1992; UA198.002.003.00007 (Box 3)
    - Statistics, 1992 -- 1993; UA198.002.003.00008 (Box 3)
    - Statistics, 1994 -- 1995; UA198.002.003.00009 (Box 3)
    - Statistics, 1995 -- 1997; UA198.002.003.00010 (Box 3)
    - Statistics - Machlup Study, 1976; UA198.002.003.00011 (Box 3)
    - University Libraries, General, 1971 -- 1980; UA198.002.003.00012 (Box 3)
    - University Library Relations, 1984; UA198.002.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Office records, 1944 -- 1959; UA198.002.002
    - Books budget, 1944 -- 1957; UA198.002.006.00001 (Box Shared 3)
    - Miscellananeous expenses, 1949 -- 1959; UA198.002.006.00002 (Box Shared 3)
    - Visitors book, 1950 -- 1958; UA198.002.006.00003 (Box Shared 3)
  - Donor and acquisition records, 1946 -- 2008; UA198.002.003
    - Fletcher endowed funds, 1951 -- 2007; UA198.002.007.00001 (Box 7)
    - Donor fund report, 2006 -- 2007; UA198.002.007.00002 (Box 7)
    - Letters to donors, 1988 -- 2008; UA198.002.007.00003 (Box 7)
    - Donor letters, 1999; UA198.002.007.00004 (Box 7)
    - Donor lists, 1993 -- 1998; UA198.002.007.00005 (Box 7)
    - Donor reports, 2001 -- 2002; UA198.002.007.00006 (Box 7)
    - Fares, 1993 -- 2006; UA198.002.007.00007 (Box 7)
    - Gifts - Misc., 2006; UA198.002.007.00008 (Box 7)
    - Gifts - Books, 1991 -- 2007; UA198.002.007.00009 (Box 7)
    - Gifts - Hill, 1999; UA198.002.007.00010 (Box 7)
    - Monetary gifts, 1996 -- 2004; UA198.002.007.00011 (Box 7)
    - Bradley, 1993 -- 2006; UA198.002.007.00012 (Box 7)
    - Cabot, 1981 -- 2007; UA198.002.007.00013 (Box 7)
    - Cummings, 1947 -- 1959; UA198.002.007.00014 (Box 7)
    - Hay, John, 2006; UA198.002.007.00015 (Box 7)
    - Imlah, 1969 -- 2001; UA198.002.007.00016 (Box 7)
    - Raanan, 2006; UA198.002.007.00017 (Box 7)
    - Roche, 1994 -- 1997; UA198.002.007.00018 (Box 7)
    - G.G. Wilson's gift collection - list, 1946; UA198.002.007.00019 (Box 7)
- Photographs and posters, 2007 -- 2010; UA198.003; 1.2 Linear Feet; 2 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains one folder of promotional posters for the Ginn Library created in 2007. There are three copies of the same poster, showing the phrase "May the Source be with You" and images of the Ginn Library staff members.
  This series consists of only one folder with one item (3 copies).
  - Promotional Posters, 2007; UA198.003.004.00001 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 8)
    3 copies of "May the Source Be With You" promotional poster; see also ARMS 13319138 for bookmarks; Moved from UA015 on 2007-12-18.
    poster
  - Ginn Library staff with Director Jeff Kosokoff, 2010-12-01; UA198.003.005.00001; Unknown
    From left to right in reverse chronological order that they worked in the Library: Daniel Hurwit, Lindsey Tapper, Linda Batista, Muriel Prentice, Linda Warner with Jeff Kosokoff in front. Taken at the retirement party for Karin McMaster, Fletcher Administrative Assistant.
    Librarians
  - Ginn Library staff, 2010-12-01; UA198.003.005.00002; Unknown
    From left to right in reverse chronological order that they worked in the Library: Daniel Hurwit, Lindsey Tapper, Linda Batista, Muriel Prentice, and Linda Warner. Taken at the retirement party for Karin McMaster, Fletcher Administrative Assistant.